sleepnumber.com 2018-12-01

# Customer Service: Privacy Policy | Sleep Number

### SLEEP NUMBER PRIVACY POLICY

We value the relationship We have with You, and We are committed to respecting the confidentiality of Your Information. We pledge that We will take reasonable steps to ensure that Your Information will only be used in ways that are in compliance with this Privacy Notice.

When We use the word “Us,” “We,” or “Our,” We mean Sleep Number Corporation, owner of the Sleep Number® retail stores, products and services. In addition, when We use the word “You” or “Your,” We mean you, as well as any child for which you are the parent or legal guardian for whom you create a User Profile (a “Child”). Capitalized terms are defined throughout this Privacy Notice.

We collect two types of information about and from You, each of which are described more fully in this Privacy Notice. Generally speaking, information that identifies You individually is referred to as Personal Information, and information that doesn’t identify You individually but is generated as a result of Your activity is referred to as Usage Information. Personal Information and Usage Information together are referred to as “Information”.

This Privacy Notice describes Our information and privacy practices with respect to Your Information for:

  * Our retail stores
  * Our websites, such as http://www.sleepnumber.com (collectively, the “Website”)
  * Our mobile applications, such as the SleepIQ® mobile application (collectively, the “App”)
  * Any online feature, service, and/or program offered by Us (collectively, with the App, the “Services”)
  * Third party social media pages that We maintain
  * Any email message that We send to You
  * Any other location, occasion, or event where Your Information is collected by or on behalf of Us

By providing Your Information to Us, You consent to the collection and use of Your Information as specified in this Privacy Notice. The Website and the App, may contain links to other websites that are operated by third parties. This Privacy Notice does not apply to, and We are not responsible for, the privacy practices or the content of these other websites. The inclusion of a link on the Website does not imply endorsement of the linked website or service by Us. Please read the privacy policies of the other websites to learn how such third parties collect, use, share, and secure information about You.

This Privacy Notice is organized as follows:

  * When is Personal Information Collected?
  * What Personal Information is Collected?
  * How is Personal Information Used?
  * Is Personal Information Shared?
  * What Usage Information is Collected?
  * How is Usage Information Collected and Used?
  * What are My Choices Regarding the Use of My Personal Information?
  * How Secure is My Personal Information?
  * Is Information from Children Collected?
  * How are My California Specific Rights Protected?
  * How are “Do Not Track” Signals Handled?
  * What if I am in the European Union?
  * What are My Responsibilities Regarding Using the Services and Security?
  * How do I Change My Contact Information?
  * Will this Privacy Notice Change?
  * End User License Agreement
  * Contact Information

#### When is Personal Information collected?

“Personal Information” is information that identifies You as an individual, or relates to an individual person. We receive Personal Information when You provide it to Us, such as when You: 

  * Place an order, such as purchasing a Sleep Number® bed or SleepIQ Kids® bed (each, a “Bed”)
  * Schedule a delivery
  * Create a Sleep Number account online or register a SleepIQ user profile in connection with your Bed (a “User Profile”) for You or a Child (online or in the App)
  * Allow any person to use the Bed while any User Profile that has data collection enabled is active
  * Participate in a sweepstakes, promotion, or survey
  * Apply for financing
  * Visit one of Our retail stores or the Website
  * Complete a warranty card or other form
  * Send an email to Us with a request for information or an inquiry
  * Call Us with a question or a concern
  * Participate in another activity with Us, such as using any of Our Services

We may also receive Personal Information about You from other sources, such as public databases, social media platforms, joint marketing partners, Our partners, or service providers.

We may provide the opportunity for You to interface with one or more third party services, such as connecting to third party applications and/or platforms (collectively, the “Third Party Services”). Your explicit consent and authorization is required for use of Your Personal Information with a Third Party Service. Once Your consent is given for a particular Third Party Service, You agree that We may receive information and data regarding You and Your use of such Third Party Service (the “Third Party Data”). This Privacy Notice governs the collection, ownership, storage, and use of Third Party Data by Us. The Third Party Service’s privacy notice or privacy policy governs the collection, ownership, storage, and use of Third Party Data by such Third Party Service. You are responsible for reading and understanding the terms, conditions, and privacy notice or privacy policy that applies to Your use of any Third Party Service and You should contact the third party with any questions about such Third Party Service. You acknowledge and agree that We are not responsible for Your use or the performance of the Third Party Services, and We make no representation or guarantee about any aspect of any Third Party Service, including, but not limited to, the accuracy, quality, or security of the Third Party Data accessed or made available by or through the any Third Party Service.

Go to Top

#### What Personal Information is collected?

We may collect Personal Information about You, which may include, among other types of information, Your:

  * Contact information, such as Your name, mailing address, shipping address, email address, and phone number
  * Demographic information, such as Your age, weight, height, and gender
  * Credit or debit card information
  * Contact information, such as the name, mailing address, shipping address, email address, and phone number, of the person to whom You had Your purchase shipped, if other than You
  * Contact information, such as name, mailing address, shipping address, email address, and phone number, and/or demographic information, such as age, weight, height, and gender, for any person for whom You create a User Profile
  * Information You provide to Us on a financing application
  * Information You provide to Us to allow Your participation in a partner’s loyalty program

Once You create a User Profile, We also may collect Personal Information, which may include, among other types of information:

  * Revised or updated User Profile information
  * Biometric and sleep-related data about how You, a Child, and any person that uses the Bed slept, such as that person’s movement, positions, respiration, and heart rate while sleeping
  * Other information You choose to provide to Us by opting in to additional functionality of Our Services, such as Your bedtime routine, so We can send You bedtime notifications and set personalized alarm clocks

If You submit any Personal Information relating to another person, such as Your spouse/partner or Child, You represent that You have the authority to do so and to permit Us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

Go to Top

#### How is Personal Information used?

We use Personal Information to better serve Our customers. For example, in addition to other uses, We may use Personal Information in order to:

  * Fulfill requests for products, services or information
  * Send administrative information to You, such as information regarding Our products and services and changes to Our terms, conditions, and policies 
  * Facilitate promotions, such as loyalty programs, referral programs, sweepstakes, surveys, and other promotions 
  * Provide customer service
  * Fulfill Our business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring, and prevention; developing improved and new products and services; determining the effectiveness of Our promotional campaigns; and expanding and operating Our business activities 
  * Send marketing communications that We believe may be of interest to You, such as by telephone, email, postal mail or other digital communications 
  * Personalize Your experience online and offline by presenting content, offers, and products tailored to You 
  * Process Your financing requests
  * To improve Our Services by determining which of Our features, products, and services are most popular 
  * Share the Information, as described in the “Is Personal Information Shared?” section below 

Go to Top

#### Is Personal Information shared?

We may disclose Your Personal Information to Our affiliates, vendors, or business partners who are acting on Our behalf. These third parties provide various services for Us, such as:

  * Sending Our marketing communications
  * Delivering packages
  * Assisting in managing customer information
  * Fulfilling information requests
  * Processing payments
  * Fulfilling promotions
  * Conducting research, analysis or administering surveys
  * Processing financing applications
  * Allowing You to participate in a partners’ loyalty programs

We may also disclose Your Personal Information to trusted third parties so that they can offer products and/or services about which they or we believe you may have an interest.

We may also disclose Your Personal Information to identify You to anyone to whom You send a message through Our Services. We may also send You emails to inform You about SleepIQ® score averages of Our users and to let You know how You compare to other users using the Services.

You may choose to disclose Your Personal Information through Our ratings and reviews pages, social media pages, and other similar services to which You are able to post information and materials. Any information that You post or disclose through these services may become public information and may be available to other users and the general public. We urge You to be very careful when deciding to disclose any information.

We may be required to share Personal Information under applicable law, including laws outside Your country of residence; or to comply with legal process or in response to a valid court order, government investigation, subpoena public and government authorities, including public and government authorities outside Your country of residence. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that We, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may, but will be under no obligation to, share Personal Information when We believe that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce Our End User License Agreement or other terms and conditions; to protect Our operations or those of any of Our affiliates; to protect the property, rights, or safety of others and Ourselves; or to allow Us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that We may sustain. We may also transfer Personal Information in the event of an acquisition, dissolution, merger, sale, or other disposition of all or any portion of Our assets, business, or stock, including a bankruptcy or similar proceeding.

In addition to the other rights herein, at all times We shall have the right to exploit, share, and use for any purpose the Personal Information collected using the Services and Third Party Data that is in an aggregated, anonymized form, such that You are not identified (collectively, “De-identified Data”).

Except as set forth in the “What are My Choices Regarding the Use of My Personal Information?” section below, We may continue to use Personal Information and the Third Party Data, and exploit, share and use your De-identified Data, after You deactivate or cancel the Services and/or Your Sleep Number account or User Profile(s).

Go to Top

#### What Usage Information is collected?

“Usage Information” is any information about or from You that does not reveal Your specific identity or is generic, which may include, among other types of information:

  * Browser and device information, such as IP address, protocol, and sequence information
  * mobile application usage information, such as use of the App
  * Information collected through cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies
  * Physical location
  * Aggregated information, such as De-identified Data

Go to Top

#### How is Usage Information Collected and Used?

We and Our third party service providers may collect Usage Information in a variety of ways, including:

Through Your browser or device: Certain information is collected by most browsers or automatically through Your device, such as Your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (e.g., Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system, browser name and version, device manufacturer, device model, and language.

Through Your use of the App: When You download and use Our App, We and Our service providers may track and collect Your mobile application usage data, such as the date and time the App on Your device accesses Our servers, what features or functionality of the App You use, the unique identifier (UDID) for Your mobile device, and what information and files have been downloaded/uploaded to the App.

Using Cookies: We use a feature of Your Internet web browser called a “cookie” to assign a unique identification to Your computer. Cookies are small data files that a website or email may send to Your browser, and which may be stored on Your hard drive. Cookies allow Us to collect information such as time spent on the Website, pages visited, language preferences, and other traffic data. We use this information to enhance Your experience on the Website, to continually improve the design and functionality of the Website, and to assist Us with resolving certain of Your questions.

We may partner with companies that facilitate relationships We have with other companies (Our marketing affiliates) that promote Us on their websites. These facilitator companies, along with Our marketing affiliates, utilize cookies to gather information concerning customer referrals from affiliate websites to the Website. This information is used to help Us fulfill Our contractual obligations to the third party marketing affiliates.

You may choose to set Your web browser to not accept cookies. If Your cookies are disabled, You can still view the Website, but some functionality may be limited, and You will not be able to create a Sleep Number account or make purchases.

Analytics: We may use third party analytics services, such as Google Analytics, in connection with the Website and other Services. Such third party services may use cookies and similar technologies to collect and analyze information about use and to report on activities and trends. Such services may also collect information regarding the use of other websites, applications, and online resources. For more information about Google Analytics, please go to www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/. You may download the Google Analytics opt out browser add-on at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

Using Pixel Tags: We also use pixel tags, which are tiny graphic images, to tell Us what parts of the Website You have visited or to measure the effectiveness of any searches You may do on the Website. Pixel tags also let Us know when You have opened an email message from Us. You may choose to disable pixel tags by setting Your browser to be in text mode only.

Using Adobe Flash technology (including Flash Local Shared Objects (“Flash LSOs”)) and other similar technologies: We may use Flash LSOs and other technologies to, among other things, collect, and store information about Your use of Our Services. If You do not want Flash LSOs stored on Your computer, You can adjust the settings of Your Flash player to block Flash LSO storage using the tools contained in the Website Storage Settings Panel. You can also control Flash LSOs by going to the Global Storage Settings Panel and following the instructions (which may include instructions that explain, for example, how to delete existing Flash LSOs (referred to as “information” on the Macromedia site), how to prevent Flash LSOs from being placed on Your computer without Your being asked, and (for Flash Player 8 and later) how to block Flash LSOs that are not being delivered by the operator of the page You are on at the time). Please note that setting the Flash Player to restrict or limit acceptance of Flash LSOs may reduce or impede the functionality of some Flash applications.

Physical Location: We may collect the physical location of Your device by, for example, using satellite, cell phone tower, or Wi-Fi signals. We may use Your device’s physical location to provide You with personalized location-based services and content. You may be permitted to allow or deny such collection and/or uses of Your device’s location, but, if You deny such collection and/or use, We may not be able to provide You with the applicable personalized services and content.

IP Address: Your IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to the computer that You are using by Your Internet Service Provider. An IP address may be identified and logged automatically in Our server log files whenever a user accesses Our online services, along with the time of the visit and the pages visited. Collecting IP addresses is standard practice and is done automatically by many websites, applications, and other services. We use IP addresses for such purposes as calculating use levels, diagnosing server problems, and administering Our online services.

Beacons: We may use beacons in Our retail locations. Beacons emit a low energy Bluetooth signal that may be detected by Your mobile device if You are within or standing outside Our store. We use beacon technology to better understand traffic patterns in and near Our stores. You can avoid a Beacon detecting Your presence by disabling Bluetooth on your mobile device(s). 

From you: Information such as Your preferred means of communication and other preferences and information is collected when You voluntarily provide it to Us.

De-identified Data: We exploit, share, and use for any purpose De-identified Data. For example, We may aggregate Personal Information to calculate the percentage of Our customers who have a particular telephone area code.

We may use and disclose Usage Information for any purpose, except where We are otherwise prohibited under applicable law. If We are required to treat Usage Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then We may collect, store, and use it for all the purposes for which We use and disclose Personal Information.

We may use comments, ideas, information, or feedback that You may submit in any manner that We may choose without notice or compensation to You.

Go to Top

#### What are My Choices Regarding the Use of My Personal Information?

Whether You submit Information to Us is entirely up to You. If you decide to not submit Information, We may not be able to provide certain features, products, and/or services to You. 

To opt out or discontinue receiving marketing communications from Us by using one of the following options:

  1. Follow the instructions in a marketing email from Us.
  2. Call 1-888-580-9237
  3. Send an email to: unsubscribe@sleepnumber.com
  4. Send a request to:  
Sleep Number Corporation  
Attn: DM Sales Support  
1001 Third Avenue South  
Minneapolis, MN 55404

Be sure to include Your current contact information, such as Your full name, address, phone number, and email address. Indicate specifically what type of marketing communication(s) and method(s) You desire to stop receiving. This will ensure We identify You correctly in Our systems and accurately process Your request. We will try to comply with Your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

Please note that even if You opt out of receiving marketing communications, You may still receive business-related notifications and communications, such as order confirmations, product recall information, loyalty program membership status and updates, and important administrative communications. There are some uses from which You cannot opt out, such as Our use of De-identified Data or to provide products and services that You have requested from Us or as described in the last paragraph of the “Is Personal Information Shared?” section above. Even if we agree to cease sharing and/or using your Personal Information, that Personal Information may not be deleted immediately, but will be deleted in accordance with our routine data retention policies in effect from time-to-time.

Go to Top

#### How Secure is My Information?

Whether You are shopping in Our stores or online, please be assured that We seek to use reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural security safeguards and take reasonable precautions to protect against the loss, misuse, and unauthorized access of Your Information under Our control. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. While We may provide certain encryption technologies and use other reasonable precautions to protect Your confidential information and provide suitable security, We do not and cannot guarantee or warrant that any information transmitted through the Internet is secure, or that such transmissions are free from delay, interruption, interception or error. If You believe that Your interaction with Us is no longer secure, please immediately contact Us in accordance with the “Contact Information” section below.

Go to Top

#### Is Information from Children Collected?

The Website is not intended to attract children under the age of 13. You will need to affirm that You are more than 18 years of age, or an emancipated minor, or possess legally sufficient parental or legal guardian consent, and are fully able and competent to enter into the terms, conditions, obligations, affirmations, representations, and warranties set forth in this Privacy Notice, and to abide by and comply with this Privacy Notice. In any case, You affirm that You are over the age 13, as THE WEBSITE IS NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN UNDER 13 WHO ARE UNACCOMPANIED BY THEIR PARENT(S) OR LEGAL GUARDIAN(S).

With respect to the Services, We may collect, store, and use Information about a Child in connection with administering and operating Our Services. Such collection occurs when You create a User Profile on behalf of Your Child in connection with the SleepIQ Kids bed or the extent you allow your child to use a Bed you purchased. We only collect personally identifiable information reasonably necessary to provide services requested by the Child’s parent(s) or legal guardian(s), and only after We receive parental/legal guardian consent for such collection. YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT THE ACT OF YOU CREATING A USER PROFILE FOR A CHILD OR OTHERWISE ALLOWING YOUR CHILD TO USE A BED IS YOUR PARENTAL/LEGAL GUARDIAN CONSENT FOR THE COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION AND USAGE INFORMATION ABOUT AND FROM THAT CHILD, AS PERMITTED IN THIS PRIVACY NOTICE.

For the avoidance of doubt, We will not intentionally collect Personal Information about children unless You create a User Profile for Your Child. We will not share personally identifiable information that We collect about a Child with third parties, except for information that We share to provide the services requested by the Child’s parent(s) or legal guardian(s) and except as provided in the “Is Personal Information shared?” section of this Privacy Notice. We do not knowingly advertise or market to children. We will maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of Information We collect about a Child, including by taking reasonable steps to release such Information only to parties capable of maintaining its confidentiality and security.

If You desire to prevent further collection of Your Child’s Personal Information, You should deactivate their User Profile. If that happens, then We will no longer be able to provide Services on behalf of Your Child. If You deactivate Your Child’s User Profile, You must uninstall the App from the device(s) used by Your Child. If You change Your mind We may not be able to reactivate the Child’s User Profile.

Parents and legal guardians should be aware that while this Privacy Notice will govern Our use of Personal Information, use of information that is voluntarily given by a Child – or others – in email exchanges, bulletin boards or the like may be used by other parties to generate unsolicited communications. We encourage all parents and legal guardians to instruct their children in the safe and responsible use of their Personal Information while using the Internet and mobile applications.

Go to Top

#### How are My California Specific Rights Protected?

Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents who provide certain personally identifiable information in connection with obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from Us (once a calendar year) information about the customer information We shared (if any) with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which We shared Your customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2017 will receive information regarding 2016 sharing activities, if any).

To obtain this information, please send an email message to Legal@sleepnumber.com with “Request for California Privacy Information” in the subject line and in the body of Your message. We will provide the requested information to You at Your email address in response. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the “Shine the Light” requirements, and only information on covered sharing will be included in Our response.

Go to Top

#### How are “Do Not Track” Signals Handled?

Note that Your browser settings may allow You to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to websites and online services You visit. There is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context. Like many websites and online services, We currently do not alter Our practices when We receive a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser. The Website and other online services do not currently have the ability to recognize or honor browser Do Not Track signals. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit www.allaboutdnt.com.

Go to Top

#### What if I am in the European Union?

The Services are only available in the United States and are not intended for use in the European Union. You can only purchase a Bed if You are located in the United States. If You are visiting the Website from the European Union and You disclose any Personal Information to Us, please note that We may collect, transfer, and continue to use Your Personal Information and/or Usage Information outside the European Union for any of the purposes described in this Privacy Notice. By using the Website and providing Us with Your Personal Information and/or Usage Information, You consent to Our collection, transfer, and continued use of such information in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

Go to Top

#### What are My Responsibilities Regarding Using the Services and Security?

Content found on www.sleepnumber.com, in Our and Our authorized dealers’ advertisements, or provided through the Services or Your Bed, is for informational purposes only, and under no circumstance should You construe such information as medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment. We do not intend for the foregoing content to replace medical care, medical diagnosis, or the relationship between You and Your physician or other medical provider. We are not a licensed medical care provider and have no expertise in diagnosing, examining, or treating medical conditions of any kind. The data generated by and through the Services or Your Bed (“Data”) should not be used in any way to diagnose or treat any medical condition. You should always consult with a physician or healthcare professional regarding any concerns You have relating to Your health, especially before You start or stop any particular health-related regimen. Never delay seeking or disregard professional medical advice because of something You have read or interpreted while using the Services or the Bed, or based on any Data.

Through Your use of the Services and/or the Bed, You may have access to certain biometric and sleep-related data regarding You and any person that uses Your Bed. We do not provide the Data in real time and the Data is not an equivalent or substitute for medical or scientific sleep monitoring analysis or techniques used by sleep doctors and scientists, such as polysomnography and actigraphy. In some cases, the Data is generated by averaging, correlating, or otherwise manipulating raw data being captured and transmitted to Your Bed. We intend the Data to be informational only and You should not use the Data as a substitute for medical care or diagnosis, including, without limitation, the proper supervision of either a medical condition or person. For example, nobody should use the Services to monitor a person of limited mobility or who is at risk of a fall to ensure that they remain in bed, or to monitor someone with sleep apnea to ensure they are breathing. We undertake no responsibility or liability with respect to use of the Data to ensure Your or any other person’s health or safety. You acknowledge and agree that the Services and the Bed do not protect Your or any other person’s health or safety. If You rely on information provided by the Services or the Bed, You do so solely at Your own risk.

To access certain features of Our Services, We may require the use of encryption technologies provided for Your protection. We use reasonable precautions to protect the privacy of Your username, password, Sleep Number account, and User Profile information and to ensure that information collected through the Services is not lost, misused or altered inappropriately by administering security measures. You are ultimately responsible for protecting Your username, password, Sleep Number account, and User Profile information from disclosure to third parties, and You are not permitted to circumvent the use of required encryption technologies. You agree to immediately notify Us of any unauthorized use of Your username, password, Sleep Number account, and/or User Profile, and/or any other breach of security.

Go to Top

#### How do I Change My Contact Information?

You can change Your contact information by logging into Your account or contacting Us in accordance with the “Contact Information” section below.

Go to Top

#### Will this Privacy Policy Change?

We reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Notice at any time, so We encourage You to review it periodically. The “Last Updated” legend at the bottom of this page indicates when this Privacy Notice was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Notice will become effective when We post the revised Privacy Notice. Your use of the Website and/or Services following these changes means that You accept the revised Privacy Notice for all previously collected Information and Information collected from You in the future.

Go to Top

#### End User License Agreement

Your use of the Services will also be governed by Our SleepIQ End User License Agreement (“EULA”) at [www.sleepnumber.com/sleepiq-end-user-agreement](https://www.sleepnumber.com/sleepiq-end-user-agreement). The terms of the EULA are hereby incorporated into this Privacy Notice by reference. You are responsible for reading, understanding, and abiding by the terms of the EULA.

Go to Top

#### Contact Information

Mail: | Sleep Number Corporation  
1001 Third Avenue South  
Minneapolis, MN 55404  
---|---  
Phone: | 1-888-250-4436  
  
Go to Top

Effective as of: November 30, 2018

Last Updated: November 30, 2018
